<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on wilkersite</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on wilkersite</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Gauging public interest in the death of Justice John Paul Stevens</title>
      <link>/post/gauging-public-interest-in-the-death-of-justice-john-paul-stevens/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/gauging-public-interest-in-the-death-of-justice-john-paul-stevens/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Justice John Paul Stevens died on July XXXX, 2019. He retired about a decade ago and was replaced by Elana Kagen on the bench. Over the last few years I have been investigating when the general public becomes interested in the Supreme Court as an institution, in the Court’s members, and in the cases that the Court decides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post I will look at interest generated by Stevens’ recent death. How do we know if the public is interested? I have explored two tools: Wikipedia page views and Google Trends. Wikipedia reports page views on a daily basis and these are relatively easy to access. Google reports web searching for terms, including people, and reports data through a variety of lenses, both short term and long term, reporting out an index with 100 being the highest search time period. I will also be looking at two measures of media coverage for comparison: cable news coverage as recorded by the XXXX and the number of news stories as collected by XXXX. For all of this data, I have gone back to the beginning of the available Wikipedia page view data, December 2007 with the exception of the cable news data which is only available from XXXX, XXXX.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A test post</title>
      <link>/post/a-test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-test-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a test post to see how to create a post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
